Gregory Johnston

Hillsborough, New Jersey

Phone: 908-635-3268 | **Email:** gjohnston47@yahoo.com **LinkedIn:** https://www.linkedin.com/in/gregory-johnston-dev/

GitHub: https://github.com/CoffeeEyes28

Summary

Full Stack Web Developer with a background in customer service and team management. Fast learner and resilient in the face of any challenge. Known amongst peers and team members as dependable and a positive influence on morale.

Technical Skills

Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node, Express, MySQL, MongoDB, React

Expertise: Team Leadership, API's, Object Oriented Programing & Object Relational Mapping

Projects

Furrever | github.com/CoffeeEyes28/Furrever | https://enigmatic-gorge-61389.herokuapp.com/

- Furrever is a web based social media platform designed to help get fostered animals adopted and provide information that will help keep them adopted.
- Roles: Project Manager, Backend Functionality
- Tools: HTML, Bulma CSS, JavaScript, Node, Express, Handlebars, Cloudinary, MySQL, Sequelize

Anonymous Profile Generator | github.com/dmerk2/Anon-Profile-Generator | dmerk2.github.io/Anon-Profile-Generator

- Anonymous Profile Generator is a web based application which will randomly generate a profile
 picture and bio asset for users to help quickly build an anonymous social media profile.
- Role: Responsible for JavaScript and Third Party API integration.
- Tools: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, Pixel Encounter API, Random Fact Generator API

Weather Pocket | github.com/CoffeeEyes28/weather-pocket | coffeeeyes28.github.io/weather-pocket/

- Weather Pocket is a web based application utilizing the Open Weather API to give users the current and future weather conditions of their queried location.
- Roles: Sole Author
- Tools: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, Moment.js, Open Weather API

Experience

Department Manager Kohl's Department Store

2013-2016

Hillsborough, NJ | Spring Hill, FL

Managed both Front End and Jewelry departments of multiple stores. Ensured departments were properly merchandised at all times, and prioritized the satisfaction of all customers. Communicated with associates to ensure they understood promotions, and worked with associates to increase sales, as well as growth of rewards and credit programs.

Jewelry Sales Consultant Belk Department Store

2016-2018

Statesboro, GA

Worked with department management to maximize customer relations, sales, and reward program growth. Also responsible for merchandising watches, and small jewelry repairs. Sold over \$100,000 worth of product within the fiscal year to be granted the title of consultant.

Shift Lead Supervisor Rite Aid Pharmacy

2018-2018

Statesboro, GA

Responsible for opening and closing the store, delegating tasks to be completed by associates, working with management to keep store merchandised, and keeping track of inventory.

Also responsible for opening and nightly deposits of all registers.

Education

Certificate of Full Stack Development: Rutgers University, New Jersey

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, Bootstrap, Node.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js, and ReactJS.